<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured on Lesley Pandian</title>
    <link>https://example.com/series/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured on Lesley Pandian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.com/series/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VR Lego Simulator</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2017/11/vr-lego-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2017/11/vr-lego-simulator/</guid>
      <description>During my Virtual Reality Course (Master&amp;rsquo;s) we had to come up with a system to construct and de-construct Lego. The project was done as a team of 3 developers and 2 artists.
The system was developed using FIVE-UDE version of Unity (A custom made Unity Version for developing application for the UTDallas Motion Capture Lab). We had access to a Motion capture Lab which used Vicon Cameras to track the motion of the users Oculus Rift (DK1) and 2 Wii Controllers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VR Augemented Desktop</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2017/09/vr-augemented-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2017/09/vr-augemented-desktop/</guid>
      <description>My thesis work was to study the trade-off between usability and fidelity in a modern VR set-up, in the domain of user training.
For the highest possible fidelity (at the time) we used the latest Oculus Rift (DK2) and a Creative DepthSense camera (depth camera) for user interaction.
Challenges:   Finger-tracking : This took a major part of the development time, getting the perfect position and filtering the tracking information for reliable and consistent tracking was a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music-Logic</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2015/12/music-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2015/12/music-logic/</guid>
      <description>During my Creative Automata class (Master&amp;rsquo;s) we had learned about Digital signals and Automata theory. At the end of the course we had to create something that represented all the things we had learned over the course. I have gotten these from pictures and files stored around my PC, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the original project unfortunately
Introduction: Playing music on any instruments and creating a song requires a sequence of instructions to be executed at certain times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>