<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Lesley Pandian</title>
        <link>https://example.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Lesley Pandian</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://example.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>VR Lego Simulator</title>
            <link>https://example.com/posts/2017/11/vr-lego-simulator/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://example.com/posts/2017/11/vr-lego-simulator/</guid>
            <description>During my Virtual Reality Course (Master&amp;rsquo;s) we had to come up with a system to construct and de-construct Lego. The project was done as a team of 3 developers and 2 artists.
The system was developed using FIVE-UDE version of Unity (A custom made Unity Version for developing application for the UTDallas Motion Capture Lab). We had access to a Motion capture Lab which used Vicon Cameras to track the motion of the users Oculus Rift (DK1) and 2 Wii Controllers.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During my Virtual Reality Course (Master&rsquo;s) we had to come up with a system to construct and de-construct Lego. The project was done as a team of 3 developers and 2 artists.</p>
<p>The system was developed using FIVE-UDE version of Unity (A custom made Unity Version for developing application for the UTDallas Motion Capture Lab). We had access to a Motion capture Lab which used Vicon Cameras to track the motion of the users Oculus Rift (DK1) and 2 Wii Controllers. The Oculus Rift (DK1) was used for visual immersion and the Wii controllers simulated the users hands &amp; inputs.</p>
<p>Given the high-precision capability of the Motion Tracking Lab, we wanted to develop an interaction technique which could replicate real life interaction with Lego. Our primary goal was to make it as realistic and natural as possible.</p>
<h3 id="lego-snapping-and-management">Lego snapping and management:</h3>
<p>Simulating Lego sounded very simple initially, but on development of the system we realized that it was extremely difficult to create a realistic snapping and unsnapping Lego system in a virtual environment.</p>
<p>There are certain points to consider when developing the Lego system:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lego as a structure does not have a parent or child relation, rather its a group of Legos. This data structure is effectively a grid. This had to be handled by the developers since almost all 3D Engines handle their 3D objects as trees.</li>
<li>In Terms of 3D graphics there must exist a parent child relation in order for the 3D Object to be rotated about a right pivot. (Hence the tree structure of 3D objects)</li>
<li>On unsnapping a given piece, all the top lego pieces it is associated with must also be part of the unsnapping. This needs to be done dynamically.</li>
<li>Unsnapping of certain lego pieces can divide the lego system into more than 2 individual groups, in such a situation how does one dynamically determine which Legos are together or not?</li>
<li>Apart from managing the Lego themselves, the lego physics (weight, bounce, gravity)needed to be simulated accurately.</li>
</ul>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/apofKuhpu0k" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-tXPMUkvb6jc/VOEFA9_no8I/AAAAAAAADoI/tMh8UfWIK8k/s1600/IMG_20150210_140440.jpg" alt="">
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-J0ApybCkijE/VOEFXxACqqI/AAAAAAAADoU/pHqJj-qiIR4/s1600/IMG_20150212_170658.jpg" alt="">
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L3Va-VNgwaQ/VOEFXz8Up_I/AAAAAAAADoY/jvU2c2-X6L8/s1600/IMG_20150212_164421.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Software packages used:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unity3D (5-UDE)</li>
<li>Blender</li>
<li>Maya</li>
<li>Photoshop</li>
</ul>
<p>Credit:</p>
<ul>
<li>Anvit Srivastav - 3D Modelling</li>
<li>Andrew Spies - Developer</li>
<li>Ravi Nankani - Developer</li>
<li>William Broderick - 3D Modelling &amp; Level Design</li>
<li>Lesley Pandian - Developer\Team Manager</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>VR Augemented Desktop</title>
            <link>https://example.com/posts/2017/09/vr-augemented-desktop/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://example.com/posts/2017/09/vr-augemented-desktop/</guid>
            <description>My thesis work was to study the trade-off between usability and fidelity in a modern VR set-up, in the domain of user training.
For the highest possible fidelity (at the time) we used the latest Oculus Rift (DK2) and a Creative DepthSense camera (depth camera) for user interaction.
Challenges:   Finger-tracking : This took a major part of the development time, getting the perfect position and filtering the tracking information for reliable and consistent tracking was a challenge.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My thesis work was to study the trade-off between usability and fidelity in a modern VR set-up, in the domain of user training.</p>
<p>For the highest possible fidelity (at the time) we used the latest Oculus Rift (DK2) and a Creative DepthSense camera (depth camera) for user interaction.</p>
<h3 id="challenges">Challenges:</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Finger-tracking : This took a major part of the development time, getting the perfect position and filtering the tracking information for reliable and consistent tracking was a challenge.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Interaction : We needed to develop an intuitive method of picking-up and attaching Lego. Since the long-term goal is to study VR training, the interaction technique must be as natural as possible and should not require any form of training.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Calibration system : To minimize ambient variables in the scene, we modeled the virtual world after the real world location where the system was intended to be used, at the same time, we wanted the option of swapping this VR world for another setting, if we so desired. For this purpose a robust and adaptive calibration system had to be designed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Real world modeling : I am not a 3D artist, most of my modeling skills are fruits of my curiosity. Please excuse the lack of fine post-process finish of the assets in the scene. My main concentration was the scale of the objects. It is paramount that the virtual environment must be inline with the real world. Having objects to scale adds a lot of fidelity and credibility to the system with little effort. Despite, the lack of realism in the lighting and finish, the scale itself would be enough to provide a high level of fidelity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Performance analysis and monitoring : Re-iterating the long term goal: VR training research. It was important to collect data, and analyse them. We needed a system which could have information relative to the actions of the person in the 3D world. At the same time, the system should assess the performance of the user.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Bear in mind that this is a work in progress, there are a lot more assets to model and bugs to fix.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XZeYEqnRLFw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-AyZjfUHa7cc/VOEypJ-sShI/AAAAAAAADo8/W4cA4UjG2Yo/s1600/IMG_20150210_123132.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Software packages used:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unity 3D</li>
<li>Intel Perceptual Computing SDK 2013</li>
<li>Blender</li>
<li>Photoshop</li>
</ul>
<p>Being a solo project I had to do a lot of research and a lot of prototyping. Trail and error, infinite failures, lack of sleep and brain killing bugs. What you see is around 30% of the total work I had done over the span of my thesis. This was my first step into the world of Research and Development, and I had an absolute blast.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Music-Logic</title>
            <link>https://example.com/posts/2015/12/music-logic/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://example.com/posts/2015/12/music-logic/</guid>
            <description>During my Creative Automata class (Master&amp;rsquo;s) we had learned about Digital signals and Automata theory. At the end of the course we had to create something that represented all the things we had learned over the course. I have gotten these from pictures and files stored around my PC, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the original project unfortunately
Introduction: Playing music on any instruments and creating a song requires a sequence of instructions to be executed at certain times.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During my Creative Automata class (Master&rsquo;s) we had learned about Digital signals and Automata theory. At the end of the course we had to create something that represented all the things we had learned over the course.
I have gotten these from pictures and files stored around my PC, I don&rsquo;t have the original project unfortunately</p>
<h3 id="introduction">Introduction:</h3>
<p>Playing music on any instruments and creating a song requires a sequence of instructions to be executed at certain times. The result of this is a song.</p>
<p>A computer is a calculator, which usually doesn&rsquo;t go wrong (mostly not at all). The inner workings of a computer can be broken down into logic gates. Obviously the system to use the gates for generic instruction sets is a lot more complex. However, it should be possible to design a basic system which shows that it is possible for such a system to exist in Music.</p>
<p>By mapping input pulses to notes it should be possible to design a system which could play music by using only Logic gates and signals . I had a guitar handy and hence I started off with it, but this principle should be possible to translate to any musical instrument. We could possibly even invent an instrument which caters to this specific use case of logic gates.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ufhgg2Nj9A" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>The initial development of the project was straight forward however, I had not taken into consideration some factor&rsquo;s during early development.</p>
<p>I was using a game engine (Unity) to develop an editor. Although Unity is very customizable, most of the heavy lifting had to be done by the developer.
Since I was effectively making an editor, I needed a was to save and load circuits the user had designing, I had come to this realization much later in development, and was not considered for the &lsquo;release&rsquo;.
The time management system of the pulse node was naive, and did not account for more complex music patterns. This greatly reduced the number of music pieces playable by the framework. Only repetitive beats would be able to be played by this framework.</p>
<p>Circuit explanation:
Each black node generates a pulse which is interpreted as a TRUE signal. While every other time it is FALSE.</p>
<p>Each node has a pre-defined start delay, and delay offset. After setting up the circuit a user would press the &ldquo;Start&rdquo; button on the top to run the timer which would then make each node count down and send pulses at the appropriate time.</p>
<p>Example:
As a benchmark I wanted to design a circuit which could play &ldquo;Smoke on the Water&rdquo; by Deep Purple.</p>
<p>Given that this type of system had not been designed before or documented properly, I had a tough time in identifying an approach which would result an optimal and extendable circuit design.</p>
<p>The simplest approach would be to use each node individually for each node, but that would increase the number of nodes used, as nodes per note. A more intuitive way was using 4 points of input (4 nodes) analogous to using 4 fingers to play the guitar.</p>
<p>For this system the timing system for the pulse nodes was a simple offset and delay timer, which would basically send periodic pulses on every delay, but the initial pulse will start by an offset timer.</p>
<p>However, this was not as simple as it seemed. Finally I came-up with this:</p>
<p>Notes to the chorus of smoke on the water – A,C,D – A,C,D#,D – A,C,D,C,A</p>
<p>A appears @ 1,4,7,11 (Offset – 1 , Delay – 3)
C appears @ 2,5,8,10(Offset – 2, Delay – 3, except the last value which has to be handled separately )
D appears @ 3,6,9,(Offset,3,Delay,3, with an exception of last note)
D# appears @ 5.5 ( Offset 5.5, Delay-11 Since it is between notes)</p>
<p>OpenGL work:
This was a really old version of unity where the 2D framework was in its infancy. The Line Renderer had not supported 2D project yet hence I had to do some interesting OpenGL work to draw a line. Give an (x1,y1) and an (x2,y2) coordinates on a screen I needed to draw a line between them.
Software used:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unity 3D</li>
<li>C#</li>
<li>Photoshop</li>
<li>Audacity</li>
</ul>
<p>Further Development ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li>The circuit is currently mapped to a Guitar. It would be interesting to see how the inputs and circuit design defer from instrument to instrument.</li>
<li>Currently the timing system is just an initial time delay and a periodic offset. This system can be further improved by having a file which defined which nodes send out pulses when. This extension would greatly extend the system beyond it limitations.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
